# SHUVANKAR DEBNATH

@ shuvankar345@gmail.com

**♥** Kolkata, India

in linkedin.com/in/shuvankardebnath



### CAREER SUMMARY

#### My career in brief

I am pursuing a Bachelor of Technology in Electrical Engineering at the Institute of Engineering and Management. As a freelancer, I have extensive experience in video editing, web development, and graphic design, showcasing proficiency in Adobe Premiere Pro, HTML, CSS, and Canva.

## **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Technology - Electrical Engineering Institute of Engineering and Management

₩ July 2023 - Present

Higher Secondary and Secondary Examination

Naihati Narendra Vidyaniketan

🗎 January 2016 - April 2023 👂 Naihati

Class X : Percentage: 76%

Class XII: Grade: B+

# **EXPERIENCE**

#### Video Editor

#### Freelancer

**♀** Online / [Offline - Kolkata]

- Editing videos over 5 years.
- Made videos of different kinds like Trailers/Teasers, Tutorials, Vlog, Short Videos, Informative Videos.
- Proficiency in Adobe Premiere Pro, Wondershare Filmora.
- Have knowledge about After Effects.

#### Web Developer

#### Freelancer

March 2023 - Present

- **♀** Online / [Offline Kolkata]
- Proficiency at HTML and CSS & to enhance my web development skills currently in the process of learning Java Script.
- Made projects like Survey form, Portfolio Page, Login Page for Competive Examination.

# **Graphics Designer & Thumbnail Designer** Freelancer & at SAE IEM Club

April 2024 - Present

Online / [Offline - Kolkata]

- · Proficient with Canva.
- Hands On experience with Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop.

# **HONORS & AWARDS**

#### **Honorary Member Offer**

• Got offer from college HOD to join club as Video Editor.

## SKILLS

#### Technical:

- Video Editing Premire Pro and Filmora
- Web Development HTML, CSS, JS
- Programming Languages Python, C
- Designing Graphics Designing & Thumbnail Designing

#### **Professional Skills:**

- Creativity
- Teamwork
- Problem Solving
- Communication

# **PROJECTS**

#### Web Development

HTML + CSS Project

- Designed a Survey form with some sets of guestions coming sequentially.
- Designed a professional Portfolio website for myself. [includes Java Script for functioning]

#### Video Editing

Filmora 9

 Created several types of videos, including Vlog, Tutorials, Reels.

#### Adobe Premire Pro

• Created Cinematic Videos, Vlog and Reels.

#### Other Projects

- Have a wide knowledge for creating Bulletin and Project Reports.
- Created PPT's according to client requirements.
- Experienced in creating many You Tube thumbnails.
- Created many Social media posts.

# **RELEVANT COURSES**

- Video Editing from You Tube
- · PPT and Word by exploring the functionality of
- HTML, CSS and JS from You Tube
- Designing from You Tube and editing photos